If a monster really is attacking Japan,
will they give us permission to engage?
もし本当に怪獣がいたら 交戦許可って下りるんですかねぇ
We'd be goners if this was a monster movie.
これが怪獣映画なら 俺達きっとやられ役だぜ
We're just there for it to kill before the Giant of Light shows up.
「光の巨人」が出てくる前の噛ませ犬だ
That's not funny.
笑えませんよ それ
Well, we'll soon know for sure.
ま なんであれ すぐにはっきりする
Take this!
そうりゃあ
It's no use.
ダメだ また元に戻ってる
It's reforming itself.
Its regenerative power is unbelievable...
なんて再生能力なの
上陸を阻むだけで精いっぱいだわ
It's taking all our efforts just to keep it from coming ashore.
I can't reach Caster like this.
あれでは キャスターを討ち取れない
This is amazing! Amazing!
すげえ すげえよ
Seriously amazing, Mister!
まじすげえよ 旦那
主はいませり 主はいませり
God is with us...
God is with us!
Utw
Presents
Will one last miracle come to pass?
あと一度だけ奇跡は起こるだろう
Ato ichido dake kiseki wa okoru darou
A gentle voice paints a twisted future
優しい声で描く歪んだ未来
Yasashii koe de egaku yuganda mirai
For the sake of a world where nobody will cry
もう誰も泣かない世界のために
Mou dare mo nakanai sekai no tame ni
Before reaching the crimson-stained sky
赤く穢された空の何処にも
Akaku kegasareta sora no doko ni mo
My cries and prayers fade and disappear
届かず消える叫びと祈り
Todokazu kieru sakebi to inori
I can go on, abandoning all consolation
慰めは捨てて行ける
Nagusame wa sutete yukeru
The beautiful moonlight shines towards the beginning and vanishes
綺麗な月の光が始まりへと沈み行く
Kirei na tsuki no hikari ga hajimari e to shizumiyuku
Into the distance
その彼方へ
Sono kanata e
I'll continue to reach out as my eyes are gradually closed
閉ざされてく瞳でまだ遠くへ手を伸ばす
Tozasareteku hitomi de mada tooku e te wo nobasu
I believe in your sorrow
君の嘆きを 信じて
Kimi no nageki wo shinjite
What a disaster.
何ということだ
聖杯戦争の長い歴史にあって この様な失態は前代未聞
In the Grail War's long history, there has never been a failure like this.
According to eyewitness reports, the
Mion River area is engulfed by a thick fog,
監視係の報告によれば 未遠川一帯は濃い霧に包まれているものの
but large numbers of bystanders are beginning to gather.
すでに多くの野次馬たちが集まり始めているようです
もはや我々だけでは対処できない
This is now beyond our ability to control.
魔術教会にも協力を要請しなければ
We'll have to request aid from the Mage's Association.
して 時臣君は
Where is Tokiomi-kun?
我が師は直ちにアーチャーと共に現場へと向いました
My master is heading there with Archer in tow.
綺礼よ
Kirei.
I will handle the cover-up.
隠蔽工作は私の方で手を打つ
お前も至急時臣君の助勢に向かうのだ
You go and assist Tokiomi-kun with all haste.
分かりました 父上
Understood, Father.
何ともはや 醜穢なる眺めよ
What a hideous sight to behold.
They may be mongrels, but they're
still supposed to be famous warriors.
いかに雑種とはいえ 少しばかりは名を馳せた猛者どもであろうに
Yet they still can't take care of that
piece of filth despite working together?
それが揃いも揃ってあのような汚物の始末に明け暮れるとは
This is depressing to watch.
嘆かわしいにも程があるな
Don't you agree, Tokiomi?
そうは思わんか 時臣
We must eliminate that monster before more witnesses see it.
これ以上の目撃者が増える前に あの怪物は抹消しなければ
遠坂家の威信に賭けて
The Tohsaka family name is at stake.
My king, that pest of a monster is tearing apart your gardens.
王よ あの巨獣は御身の庭を荒らす害獣でございます
どうか手ずからの誅戮を
I implore you to execute it.
That would be a gardener's work.
そんなものは庭師の仕事だ
Or are you insinuating that my Noble Phantasm is nothing more than a gardener's shovel?
それとも時臣 よもや貴様は
オレの宝具を庭師の鋤も同然と愚弄したいのか
Not at all!
滅相もありません
しかし 御覧の通り 他の者どもでは手に余る有様です
But as you can see, the others are unable to handle it themselves.
This is an excellent chance to display the power of a true Hero.
真の英雄たる神威を知らしめる好機です
I beg you...
どうか ご英断を
Whoa!
That's ridiculous...
馬鹿な
We're leaving, Tokiomi.
引き上げるぞ 時臣
もはやあの汚物は見るに耐えぬ
I can't bear to look at that nauseating thing any longer.
No...
そんな 英雄王 どうかお待ちを
King of Heroes, please wait!
時臣 お前への義理立てと思って宝剣宝槍の四挺を使い捨てた
Tokiomi, I've already sacrificed four of my swords and spears for you.
あんなものに触れて穢れた以上は もう二度と回収する気にもならぬ
Now that they have touched that thing, I no longer desire their return.
オレの寛容を安く見るでない
Do not impinge further on my generosity.
あの怪物を倒しうる英雄は 御身しかあらせられませぬ
You are the only Hero capable of defeating that monstrosity!
あれほどの再生力がある以上
Given how rapidly it regenerates, it must be completely destroyed with a single attack!
奴の総体を一撃のもとに消し飛ばすしかない
And the only thing capable of that,
King of Heroes, is your Sword of Rupture-
それが叶うとすれば英雄王 御身の「乖離剣」をおいて他には…
痴れ者が
How dare you!
我が至宝たる「エア」をここで抜けと
You would have me draw my greatest treasure, Ea, here?!
Know your place, Tokiomi!
弁えよ時臣
Such remarks to a king are punishable by death!
王に対してその妄言 刎頸にも値するぞ
I could use a Command Spell, but that would severely damage my relationship with the King of Heroes.
令呪を使う手もあるが
間違いなく英雄王との関係は決裂してしまう
そもそも 失った令呪を取り戻すために
Furthermore, Father Risei and I devised this entire plan to restore my lost Command Spell to begin with.
璃正神父と計ったキャスター討伐のはずが
Why did everything have to backfire?
なぜこうも思惑が裏目に出る
くそう
Damn it...
What's... that?
何だ あれは
There's a strange light at six o'clock, too.
六時方向にも 妙な光が浮いてます
That's no helicopter.
ヘリじゃない
Is it a UFO or something?
UFOか何かですか あれ
コントロールよりディアボロⅠ 状況を報告されたし
Control to Diablo-1. What is your situation?
報告は いや その
My situation...
Um... Well...
I'll drop altitude and get a little closer!
もう少し高度を下げて接近してみます
W-Wait, Kobayashi!
ま 待て 小林
戻って来い ディアボロⅡ
Get back here, Diablo-2!
If I get closer, I should be able to see what it-
もっと間近からの視認なら あれが何なのかが
小林
Kobayashi?!
Kobayashi!
小林ーー
なんて奴だ
Would you look at that...
I-It ate the plane...
た 食べた
Control to Diablo-1!
コントロールよりディアボロⅠ いったい何が起こってる
What the hell is happening up there?
Report!
報告を
Eyes...
目だ 目がある そこいらじゅうにびっしりと
There are eyes...
Eyes everywhere!
Eyes? What do you mean by eyes?
目 目とは何だ
Is it going to eat me too?
この俺も食らう気なのか
First Lieutenant Ougi!
仰木一尉
Diablo-1, engaging!
ディアボロⅠ 交戦開始
W-Wait, Ougi!
ま 待て仰木 いったい何が
What's happ-
I'll kill it before it eats me.
食われる前に 殺す
I'll avenge Kobayashi.
小林の仇だ
I'll hit it with everything I have!
全弾を叩き込んでやる
Berserker?
バーサーカー
What is he doing here?
何しに現われたんだ アイツ
馬鹿もの
Fool!
乗り出すでない
Stay down!
この期に及んでまた奴か
What a time for him to show up.
あれは
That's...
Oh? It's the mad dog again.
またしてもあの狂犬か
Interesting.
面白い
My king, I shall engage his Master.
王よ 私はマスターの相手を
Very well.
良かろう 遊んでやるがいい
Go and play with him.
Good luck, then.
それでは ご武運を
Dogs like you should stay flat on the ground.
地に伏すが相応の犬の分際で 王の舞う天に昇るとは
Yet you dare to fly in the heavens, where the king dwells?
How arrogant of you, mongrel!
粋がるなよ 雑種が
Impudent brat...
ちょこざいな
面白い
Fascinating.
I haven't enjoyed myself like this for a long time.
こういう趣向の戯れ合いは久しいぞ
たかが獣ごときの分際で 随分と興じさせるではないか
For a mere beast, you do keep me quite entertained.
変わり果てたな
You've certainly changed for the worse, Matou Kariya.
間桐雁夜
You abandoned the path of magic,
but were still drawn to the Grail.
ひとたび魔道を諦めておきながら 聖杯に未練を残し
そんな姿になってまで舞い戻るとは
And now, you've returned looking like that.
今の君一人の醜態だけでも
Your disgraceful behavior reflects very poorly on the Matou.
間桐の家は堕落の謗りを免れんぞ
遠坂時臣 質問は一つだ
Tohsaka Tokiomi, I have one question for you.
なぜ貴様は桜を臓硯の手に委ねた
Why did you give Sakura to Zouken?
何
What?
それはいま君がこの場で気にかけるべき事柄か
Is that something you should be concerned about right now?
Answer me, Tokiomi!
答えろ 時臣
問われるまでもない 愛娘の未来に幸あれと願ったまでのこと
There is nothing to say.
I simply wanted a bright future for my daughter.
何だと
What?
二子を設けた魔術師は いずれ誰もが苦悩する
Any Mage with two children faces a painful dilemma.
秘伝を伝授しうるのは一人のみ
Only one may inherit the family secrets.
いずれか一人は凡俗に堕とさねばならないというジレンマにな
The other must fall to the rabble.
My wife's womb was too bountiful.
とりわけ わが妻は母体として優秀すぎた
凛も 桜も ともに等しく稀代の素養を備えて産まれてしまったのだ
Both Rin and Sakura were born with a rare level of potential.
Both daughters needed the protection a Mage clan can provide.
娘たちは二人が二人とも 魔道の家門による加護を必要としていた
いずれか一人の未来のために
To destroy the potential held by one for the sake of the other's future...
もう一人が秘め持つ可能性を摘み取ってしまうなど
親として そんな悲劇を望む者がいるものか
Would any father desire that kind of tragedy?
凡俗
The rabble...
あの遠い日の母と子の姿を
The mother and daughters I saw that day...
この男は
He simply dismisses them as rabble?!
ただ凡俗とだけ切り捨てるのか
To fulfill my wish that both their talents be developed, I had no choice but to send one for adoption.
姉妹双方の才能について望みを繋ぐには
養子に出すしか他にない
だからこそ間桐の申し出は天恵に等しかった
That's why the Matou family's request was like a blessing from heaven.
聖杯の存在を知る一族であれば
As a clan that knows of the Grail, their odds of reaching the Root are that much greater.
それだけ根源に至る可能性も高くなる
魔術師とは生まれ付いてより力ある者
All Magi are born with power,
and they will all someday attain even greater power.
そしていつしか更なる力へと辿り着く者
その運命を覚悟するより以前から
Even before they are aware of this fate, the responsibility lies in their blood.
その責任は血の中にある
That's what it means to be born a Mage's child.
それが魔術師の子として生まれるということだ
私が果たせなくても 凛が
If I cannot attain it, Rin will.
And even if Rin cannot, Sakura will.
そして凛ですら至らなかったなら桜が
遠坂の悲願を継いでくれることだろう
They will carry on the wishes of the Tohsaka family.
You...
貴様
相争えというのか 姉と妹で
You'd make the two sisters fight each other?!
仮にそんな局面に至るとしたら
Even if that really happens, my descendants will still be happy.
我が末裔たちは幸せだ
何
What?
栄光は勝てばその手に
Glory will go to whoever wins.
The loser will rest, knowing it went to the family.
負けても先祖の家名にもたらされる
かくも憂いなき対決はあるまい
Could a more joyous battle exist?
You're insane!
貴様は狂っている
語り聞かせるだけ無駄な話だ
It wasn't even worth the explanation.
魔道の尊さを理解せず
Not for one oblivious to the nobility of magic...
...let alone a traitor who turned his back on it.
あまつさえ一度は背を向けた裏切り者にはな
Shut up-
ほざけえ
I won't forgive any of you.
俺は貴様らを許さない
薄汚い魔術師どもめ
You disgusting Magi...
殺してやる
I'll kill you.
Zouken and you, both!
臓硯も 貴様も
一人残らず 殺し尽くす
I will kill...
...every last one of you!
君が家督を拒んだことで
You refused to carry on the Matou line,
so the magic of the family went to Sakura.
間桐の魔術は桜の手に渡った
むしろ感謝するべき筋合いとはいえ
I should be thanking you instead.
それでも私は
Even so...
君という男が許せない
I cannot forgive you.
血の責任から逃げた軟弱さ
Your weakness, in running from the responsibility of your blood.
そのことに何の負い目も懐かぬ卑劣さ
Your baseness, in failing to see anything wrong with doing so.
間桐雁夜は魔道の恥だ
Matou Kariya shames the paths of magic.
Now that we meet again, what else could I do but kill you?
再び相見えた以上
もはや誅を下すしかあるまい
Shut the hell up...
ふざけるな
この人でなしが
You inhuman monster!
No.
違うね
自らに責任を負うのが人としての第一条件だ
Taking responsibility for yourself is the first condition for humanity.
それが果たせない者こそ
Anyone unable to do even that...
人以下の狗だよ
...is nothing but a dog, Kariya.
雁夜
Insects, devour him.
蟲どもよ 奴を喰らえ
Devour him to death!
喰らい殺せ
やっちまえ 青髭の旦那
Get 'em, Mister Bluebeard!
ぶっ潰せ ぶっ殺せ
Crush 'em! Kill 'em!
ここは神様のオモチャ箱だ
This whole place is God's toy box!
Saber!
セイバー
忝ない セイバー
I'm in your debt, Saber!
もう退屈なんてさよならだ
I can say goodbye to boredom.
I don't have to go out of my way to kill people anymore.
手間暇かけて人殺しなんてすることもねぇ
I can just sit back and watch people die.
放っておいてもガンガン死ぬ
潰されて 千切られて 砕かれて 食われて
Crushed...
Torn apart...
Smashed...
Eaten!
They'll die, and die, and die!
死んで 死んで 死にまくる
I'll see all kinds of guts and gore I've never seen before...
まだ見たことない腸も次から次へと見られるんだ
毎日 毎日
Every day, every day...
世界中 そこいらじゅうで
Around the world! Everywhere!
Forever, never endi-
引っ切りなしの終わりなし
It stopped?
止まった
Huh?
何
ねえ 何
Hey, what was that?
すっげえ綺麗
It's so pretty...
そっか そりゃ気付かねえよな
I see...
I guess that's why I never noticed.
Sometimes you can't see what's right in front of you.
灯台下暗しとは良く言ったもんだぜ
誰でもねえ
The thing I was searching for...
俺の腸の中に
探し求めてたものが隠れてやがったんだ
...was in my own guts...
...this whole time...
ほおう 龍之介
Ryuunosuke?
やっと見つけたよ
I've finally found you.
ずっと探してたんだぜ
I had been looking for you forever...
What the hell?
なんだよ
俺の中にあるなら あるって
If you were inside me...
言ってくれりゃあいいのにさあ
...you could've just told me...
龍之介 我がマスターよ
Ryuunosuke, my Master.
私を残して先に逝くとは
You have died and left me all alone.
But don't worry, Ryuunosuke.
ですが 龍之介 ご心配なく
このジル·ド ·レェ
I, Gilles de Rais, will fulfill my promise to you.
あなたとの約束は果たしますゆえ
龍之介よ  照覧したまえ
Behold, Ryuunosuke!
私からの手向けを
A gift to see you to the next world...
The greatest COOL!
最高のクーーールを
I've shot down the man we believed to be Caster's Master.
キャスターのマスターとおぼしき男を射殺したところだが
Looks like we were right.
どうやら 当たりだったようだ
While the Servants are dealing with the monster,
サーヴァントたちが怪物に引き付けられている隙に
shall we eliminate our next target?
次のターゲットを処理しますか
Wait, Maiya.
待て 舞弥
That's no mere monster.
あれはただの化け物じゃない
無限再生を繰り返す不死の怪物だ
It's an immortal creature, infinitely regenerative.
It will reach the shore before it vanishes.
消失する前に河岸に辿り着くのは目に見えている
それで捕食を開始したら終わりだよ
If it starts feeding, it's all over.
With a new source of mana, Caster can sustain materialization.
新たな魔力源を得たキャスターは現界し続ける
そうなれば 被害はますます拡大し
And the damage would spread.
The Holy Grail War itself may need to be abandoned.
聖杯戦争そのものが破綻する恐れが出てくる
そういうことだ
That's correct.
ですが 不死の怪物をどうやって
But how do we defeat an immortal monster?
奴を一気に消滅させるしか手はない
Our only option is to exterminate it in one go.
To destroy every last piece of it in a single strike.
それにはただ一撃のもとに全身を 一片の肉片も残さず 焼き払う
対人宝具でも 対軍宝具でもない
We need a Noble Phantasm not for destroying people or armies, but fortified structures.
対城宝具が必要だ
セイバーには
Saber has one of those.
その対城宝具がある
今はランサーの槍の呪いで使えないがな
However, Lancer's curse leaves her unable to use it.
I think...
ここは一つ 奴らの騎士道精神とやらを見せてもらおうじゃないか
I'll have them show us this chivalry they're so proud of.
Episode 14
The Mion River Battle
Doushite sora wa konnani aokute
どうして空はこんなに青くて
Why is the sky so blue?
Nanimo kanashimi wo shiranu you ni
何も悲しみを知らぬように
As if oblivious to sadness
Itsumo tamerawazu ashita e to kuzureochiru
いつも躊躇わず明日へと崩れ落ちる
It crumbles incessantly to make way for a new day
Inochi wa tarinai mama umarete kuru no ne
命は足りないまま生まれてくるのね
I suppose we are born with our lives short
Kakeochita kokoro ni anata ga furete
かけおちた心にあなたが触れて
You have touched my torn heart
Futari de yuku mirai wa kegare no nai tsuyosa de
二人で行く未来は穢れのない強さで
Our future ahead is filled with a pure, unblemished strength
Sora wa takaku kaze wa utau
空は高く 風は歌う
The sky is vast, the wind is melody
Yume wo miteta yorokobi e to
夢を見てた喜びへと
Men will one day come to realize
Hito wa itsuka tadoritsukeru
人はいつか辿り着ける
The joy of chasing after a dream
Kodomo no hitomi de anata wa shinjita
子供の瞳であなたは信じた
With the eyes of a child, you've always had faith
Soba ni iru yo
そばにいるよ
I'll be right beside you
Kooritsuita mori wo nukete
凍りついた森を抜けて
As we pass through the frozen forest
Sono hitomi ga sekai no nageki ni mayowanu you ni
その瞳が世界の嘆きに迷わぬように
So that the world's sorrow will not taint your eyes
この光は
This light...
無駄な足掻きを
Such pointless struggling.
The undefeated king sings aloud the
name of the miracle she holds in her hands.
常勝の王は高らかに 手に執る奇跡の真名を謳う
痛ましくて見るに耐えん
It is too painful to look upon.
自滅する気か
Is he trying to kill himself?
ここで食い止めなければ
We must stop him here!
I'm counting on you, Saber.
Next Episode
Golden Brilliance
頼んだぞ セイバー